Guide to the Sam Adams Darcy Papers TAM.124
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Samuel Adams Darcy Papers
1924-1985
1930-1945
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Darcy, Samuel, 1905-
TAM.124
9 Linear Feet in 6 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 4 oversize folders.
Sam Adams Darcy (1905-2005), born Samuel Dardeck in the Ukraine of Jewish background, was an organizer, orator, writer, a leading official of the CPUSA and an official in the Communist International. Darcy helped organize the first mass demonstration of unemployed in New York City, was chairperson of the Communist Party California during the 1934 San Francisco General Strike, and made an unsuccessful run for governor of California in 1934. In 1941, Darcy was imprisoned briefly for allegedly falsifying information on his voter registration form. He left the CPUSA in 1945. The papers contain correspondence, writings (unpublished and published), CPUSA internal documents, clippings, ephemera, photographs, and an oral history transcript. Best documented are Darcy's educational, electoral and labor activity, and intra-Party relationships and struggles.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Samuel Adams Darcy in 1985; additional materails were donated were donated during the 1990s and by his daughter in 2007. The accession numbers associated with the gifts are 1950.257, 1985.001, 1985.008, 1985.011, NPA.2007.029, and 1009.056.
Arrangement
Organized into nine series: I. Communist Party material; II. Expulsion from CPUSA; III. Correspondence; IV. Political Activities; V. Trials; VI. Biographical Manuscripts; VII. Additional Correspondence; VIII. Photographs and Graphics; IX. Unprocessed Materials.
Folders in series I-VIII are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading within each series.
Historical/Biographical Note
Sam Adams Darcy (1905-2005), born Samuel Dardeck in the Ukraine of Jewish background was a leading official of the CPUSA for some twenty years (1925-44), and also held a number of important positions in the Communist International. Darcy was an effective organizer, talented public speaker and a prolific and vivid writer with a flair for dramatization. From 1925-27 he was head of the Party's youth organization, the Young Workers League. Along with William Z. Foster, his friend and ally in intra-party struggle against CP head Earl Browder, he organized in New York City in March 1930 the first mass unemployed demonstration.
From 1931-36 Darcy headed the second largest Party district, California, where he personally participated in the organizing of agricultural workers and the related successful struggle against California's criminal syndicalism law. As head of the California Party organization, he also played a leading role in the longshore and San Francisco general strike of 1934. That year Darcy was the Party's gubernatorial candidate, after unsuccessfully arguing within the party's central committee for a united front with Upton Sinclair's EPIC (End Poverty in California) movement.
Darcy's visibility in California was a factor in his becoming one of several Party leaders who faced legal action after the Russo-German treaty of 1939 placed the CPUSA in sharp opposition to American foreign policy. In September 1940 Darcy was indicted on charges of perjury for allegedly having incorrectly stated his name and birthplace in registering to vote in California in 1934, and spent six weeks in jail, until September 1941.
From 1939-44 Darcy led the Party's fourth largest district, Eastern Pennsylvania, and was heavily involved in electoral work, notably the Party's campaign to defeat the 1943 Democratic nominee for mayor of Philadelphia, William C. Bullitt. Darcy's continuing interest in educational work was reflected in his role as leader of the New York Workers School in 1930, CP National Education Director (1938), and in numerous lectures given at Party run workers schools in New York, San Francisco and Philadelphia. Darcy also maintained friendships and correspondence with a number of important non-communist progressives, including author Lincoln Steffens, songwriter Yip Harburg and Otto Nathan, executor of the estate of Albert Einstein.
In 1927-28 and again in 1935-38 Darcy worked in Moscow for the Communist International, serving during his second trip as head of its Anglo-American secretariat, after attending the 7th congress of the CI as a delegate from the US. On both occasions Darcy met with Stalin.
In early 1944 Darcy and Foster stood alone among the Party leadership in opposition to Browder's estimation of the prospects for post-war American-Soviet harmony. While Foster retreated in the face of overwhelming opposition, Darcy resigned his party offices in protest and shortly thereafter was expelled from the CPUSA by the vote of a commission which his friend Foster was required to chair. Although politically vindicated a year later when Browder was removed from the Party leadership, Darcy did not rejoin the party. Among the factors for this were his belief that the repudiation of Browder's policies was incomplete, and a request by the new leader, Eugene Dennis, to examine a manuscript Darcy had been working on since his expulsion. Darcy for a time maintained some contacts with other "left-wing" expellees, such as William Dunne and Charles Keith. He later became a successful furniture merchant and became active in the Democratic party.
Chonology
1917: Joins Young Peoples Socialist League (YPSL)
1921: Joins Workers Party (later Communist Party), December, 1921
1925-27: Head, Young Workers League (later Young Communist League); on CPUSA Politburo as YWL representative
1926: Marries Emma Blechschmidt
1927-28: On exec. committee, Young Communist International; Moscow, chair International Childrens Committee (YCI); travels to China and Philippines
1929-30: New York City; briefly editor of the Daily Worker, head NY Workers school
1930: Head; International Labor Defense
1931-36: Head; California district, CPUSA (also included Nevada and Arizona)
1935-38: Moscow; 7th congress Communist International, head, Anglo-American Secretariat
1938: CPUSA National Edcuation Director; Central Committee representative for Minnesota-Wisconsin-Dakotas district
1938-39: Demoted form full Central Committee member to alternate
1929-44: Eastern Pennsylvania district head
1944: Expelled from CPUSA
1945: Declines to rejoin CPUSA
Sources:
''Agricultural strikes,'' Party Organizer, Aug-Sep (1933), 82-83.
''The big stick in Latin America - its size and cost,'' Workers Monthly, March (1926), 215-218.
The Battle for Production (New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1942), 47 pp.
The Challenge of Youth; Why Every Young Worker Should Join the Young Workers Communist League (Chicago, Ill., Young Workers Communist League of America, 1926), 52 p.
''The elections in Philadelphia,'' The Communist, December (1943), 1121-1132.
An Eye_Witness at the Wreckers' Trial (New York: Workers Library Publishers, 1937), 63 p.
''The Great West Coast Maritime Strike,'' The Communist, 13:7 (1934), 664-686.
Introduction to Politics. Part 1, A Critique of American Capitalism, assisted by Ernest Pendrell. (Philadelphia, Pa.: Philadelphia Workers School and School of Social Science, 1940), 174, [1] leaves.
''Join the army-,'' Workers Monthly, May (1926), 315-318.
''Native daughter-Communist Party founder and leader,'' Communist, Oct (1942), 849-856. Anita Whitney.
''The San Francisco Bay Area General Strike,'' The Communist, 13:10 (1934), 985-1004.
Late Afternoon for the Nation_State; A Study of the Origins, Growth, Present Position and Possible Future of the Nation_State as a Form of Social Organization (New York, Cromwell Books, 1972), 408 p.
''What's Happening in the U.S.S.R? (New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1937), 15 pp.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The William Francis Dunne Papers, TAM 145
The Cedric Belfrage Papers, TAM 143
Oral History of the American Left, OH 002
Scope and Content Note
The Papers contain correspondence, writings (unpublished and published), CPUSA internal documents, clippings, ephemera, photographs, and an oral history transcript. Best documented are Darcy's educational, electoral and labor activity, and intra-Party relationships and struggles. The principal correspondents, in addition to William F. Dunne and William Z. Foster are: Israel Amter, Roger Baldwin, Max Bedacht, Cedric Belfrage, Earl Browder, Eugene Dennis, Leo Gallagher, Yip Harburg, Roy Hudson, Robert Minor, Tom Mooney, Otto Nathan, Scott Nearing, Mike Quinn, Nat Ross, William Schneiderman, Jack Stachel, Lincoln Steffens, Peter Steffens, and Ella Winter (widow of Lincoln Steffens).
Communists -- United States.; Photographs.; Correspondence.; Labor unions and communism -- United States.; Collages (visual works); Foster, William Z., 1881-1961; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973; Dennis, Eugene, 1905-1961.; Belfrage, Cedric, 1904-1990.; Harburg, E. Y. (Edgar Yipsel), 1898-1981; Communist Party of the United States of America (Penn.); Communist Party of the United States of America; Schneiderman, William; Bedacht, Max, 1883-1972; Darcy, Samuel, 1905-; Nathan, Otto, 1893-1987.; Communist Party of the United States of America (Calif.)
- Series l. Communist Party material. 1937-1946., 57421
  Scope and Content Note
  Series l (Communist Party material, 1937-1946) contains reports and speeches by Darcy to state and national CPUSA meetings. Subjects best documented are Party education and Pennsylvania electoral politics. Also contains various memos, reports, resolutions and ephemeral publications of state and national Party organizations.
  - Leadership list, undated; 57429 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - SAD talks at national meetings, 1937; 57428 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - SAD talks at Pennsylvania district meetings., 1938-1939; 57427 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SAD report for Pennsylvania state convention, 2/27/43, 1943; 57426 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SAD at Pennsylvania state committee meeting, 11/6/43, 1943; 57425 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - CPUSA, Pennsylvania, 1943-1944; 57424 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CPUSA, national, 1934-1946; 57423 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CPUSA, national (ballot), [1934]; 479076 (Box MSOS004, Folder 3)
  - New York branch meeting, 1945; 57422 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II. Expulsion from CPUSA. 1944-1945., 57417
  Series 2 (Expulsion from CPUSA, 1944-1945) contains excerpts from Darcy's criticism of Earl Browder at Politburo meeting, February 8, 1944, and correspondence relating to Darcy's expulsion and possible readmission.
  - SAD at 2/8/44 Politburo meeting, 1944; 57420 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Expulsion, 1944-1945; 57419 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Readmission, 1945; 57418 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series III. Correspondence. 1929-1985., 57375
  Series 3. Correspondence, 1929-1985: Especially rich documentation is to be found in Darcy's correspondence with the national Party leadership (subseries A) and with William Z. Foster (see subseries B).
  Arrangement
  This series is divided into six subseries. They are: A. National Office. 1930-1943; B. Individual correspondents. 1929-1983; C. Darcy jail correspondence with defense organizations, 1941; D. CPUSA years (alphabetical). 1931-1944; E. CPUSA years (chronological- names not known). 1929-1945; F. Post-CPUSA years (alphabetical). 1950-1985.
  - Subseries A. National Office, 57415
    - National Office, 1930-1943; 57416 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Subseries B. Individual Correspondents, 57384
    - Amter, Israel, 1930; 57414 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bachrach, Marion, undated; 57413 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baldwin, Roger, 1929; 57412 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bedacht, Max, 1932-1972; 57411 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1970-1982; 57410 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Browder, Earl, 1931-1938; 57409 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dennis, Eugene, 1943; 57408 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dolsen, James, 1941; 57407 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Duclos, Jacques, 1945; 57406 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dunham, Barrows and Alice, 1963-1985; 454749 (Box 1, Folder 21A)
    - Dunne, William, 1932-1948; 57405 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Foster, William Z., 1931-1945; 57404 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Gallagher, Leo, 1940-1962; 57403 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Harburg, Yip, 1954-1981; 57402 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Harris, Lem, 1938; 57401 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hudson, Roy, 1940; 57400 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Loenfels, Walter, 1941; 57399 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Minor, Robert, 1933-1934; 57398 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Mooney, Tom, 1938; 57397 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Nathan, Otto, 1975-1983; 57396 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Nearing, Scott, 1963-1972; 57395 (Box 1, Folder 31A)
    - Quinn, Mike, 1937-1941; 57394 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Rapport, xx, 1931; 57393 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Ross, Nat, 1938; 57392 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Schneiderman, William, 1937-1941; 57391 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Stachel, Jack, 1931; 57390 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, 1934; 57389 (Box 1, Folder 36A)
    - Steffens, Peter, 1942; 57388 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Tallentire, Norman, 1945; 57387 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Timber Workers Union, local 29Timber Workers Union, local 29, 1941; 57386 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Winter, Ella (Lincoln Steffen's widow), 1941; 57385 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Subseries C. Correspondence with Legal Defense Organizations, 57382
    - Darcy jail correspondence with defense organizations, 1941; 57383 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Subseries D. CPUSA years (alphabetical), 57380
    - CPUSA years (alphabetical), 1931-1944; 57381 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Subseries E. CPUSA years (chronological, names unknown), 57378
    - CPUSA years (chronological, names unknown), 1929-1945; 57379 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Subseries F. Post-CPUSA years (alphabetical), 57376
    - Post-CPUSA years (alphabetical), 1950-1985; 57377 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Political Activities. 1924-1958., 57309
  Series 4 (Political Activities, 1924-1958) contains numerous articles, lectures and speeches by Darcy, files on various events, subjects and activities, and memorabilia. Among Darcy's extensive interests those best documented by his writings are military strategy, non-Party leftist tendencies, and in addition, his trade union, electoral and educational activities, which are well documented by the series taken as a whole.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - McNamara case, undated; 57374 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 57373 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Young Pioneers/Young Workers League, 1924-1926; 57372 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Articles, clippings, 1926; 57371 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Articles, clippings, 1927; 57370 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The first subbotnik and the latest (Moscow), 1927-1928; 57369 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - On child labor, 1928; 57368 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Philippines, 1928-1929; 57367 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Articles, clippings, 1929; 57366 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1930; 57365 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - International Labor Defense, 1930; 57364 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - SAD article vs. Lovestoneites, 1930; 57363 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - May Day, New York City, 1930; 57362 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Unemployment and Democracy, 1930; 57361 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Workers School, New York City, 1930; 57360 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Working Class Education Conference (New York City), 1930; 57359 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Insufficient organization in L.A. Section, 1930; 57358 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Dialectcs, 1931; 57357 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Not Hillquit alone, but the Socialist Party, 1931; 57356 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Sugar industry workers, 1931; 57355 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Unemployed/Hunger movement, California, 1931-1932; 57354 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Erickson, Oscar, ca.1931-1933; 57353 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Fallacy of technocracy, ca.1931-1933; 57352 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Economics, 1931-1935; 57351 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Flyers, California, 1931-1935; 57350 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Socialist Party and Trotskyism, 1931-1935; 57349 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Radio speeches, 1932-1933; 57348 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Strikes, California, 1932-1933; 57347 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural strikes, California, 1933; 57346 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Symposium on culture, San Francisco, 1933; 57345 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Thomas-Steffens debate, 1933; 57344 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - NRA; the pyramiding of the crisis, ca.1933-1934; 57343 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - SAD gubernatorial campaign, 1934; 57342 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Maritime and General Strike, 1934; 57341 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - Report on general strike, 1934; 57340 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The lesson of the recent strike and the general strike, 1934; 57339 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Clippings: California Strikes, Anti-Fascism, 1934-1943; 479071 (Box MSOS004, Folder 1)
  - Next step forward in the US (N. Americus), 1935; 57338 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - The Communist Party of the United States of America, 1936; 57337 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Minnesota activities, 1936-1938; 57336 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Andre Marty interview, ca.1937; 57335 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Against Trotskyism, Bukharin, ca.1937; 57334 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Radek-Piatakov trial, notes on, 1937; 57333 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Pennsylvania, articles and speeches, 1937-1943; 57332 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pennsylvania, flyers, memorabilia, 1937-1944; 57331 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Isolation, mother of militarism, 1938; 57330 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Lovestoneism and Trotskyism, 1938; 57329 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Since 1848; ninety years of our movement, 1938; 57328 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - History of Communist Party in California, 1939; 57327 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Lenin memorial speech, Philadelphia, 1939; 57326 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Russo-German Treaty, speech, 1939; 57325 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Fall of France, speech, 1940; 57324 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - World War II, miscellaneous writings, 1940-1943; 57323 (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
  - The outlook for the war, 1941; 57322 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Relation of forces in war/domestic class relations, 1941; 57321 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Browder, Earl; "Negro people and the war", 1943; 57320 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Browder, Earl; "Teheran, history's greatest turning point", 1943; 57319 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bullitt, William C., mayoral campaign (anti), 1943; 57318 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Daily Worker 20th anniversary speech, 1943; 57317 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - United Mine Workers, Lewis and World War II, 1943; 57316 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - SAD re: Teheran Declaration, Duclos letter, 1944-1945; 57315 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to Bill Dunne's booklet ca. 1946-47, 1947; 57314 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Browder, Earl; "World communism and America", 1947; 57313 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - One hundred years of Marxism, ca.1948; 57312 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bridges, Harry, ca.1949; 57311 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Recent changes in the USSR, 1958; 57310 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Series V. Trials. 1932-1941., 57302
  Series 5 (Trials. 1932-1941) contains Darcy's notes on his defense, jail notes, defense committee materials, testimony, and clippings pertaining to Darcy's criminal syndicalism and perjury trials, and to a 1932 criminal syndicalism trial at which Darcy appeared as a defense witness.
  - Long Beach, California trial, 1932; 57308 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Criminal Syndicalism, 1934-1935; 57307 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Perjury trial, defense literature, 1940-1941; 57306 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Perjury trial, SAD notes., 1940-1941; 57305 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Perjury trial, SAD jail notes., 1940-1941; 57304 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Perjury trial, CPUSA assessment, 1941; 57303 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series VI. Biographical and other manuscripts., circa 1945-1971; 57253
  Series 6 (Biographical and other manuscripts, circa 1945-1971) contains "The Storm Must Be Ridden" (unpublished book-length political-autobiographical typescript, incomplete, circa 1945); oral history interview transcripts and notes, 1969-71; "Tales of Three Worlds" (unpublished book-length political-autobiographical typescript, circa 1960-63); a play and poetry; miscellaneous post-1945 notes.
  - Subseries A. "The storm must be ridden" (ca 1945?), 57274
    - Table of contents, undated; 57301 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - SAD biographical chronology, 1905-1939; 57300 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Chapter unknown #1, undated; 57299 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Chapter unknown #2, undated; 57298 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 1 "this much is family lore", undated; 57297 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 2 "New York City", undated; 57296 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 3 "rise and decline of the Socialist Party", undated; 57295 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 4 "painful birth of the left wing", undated; 57294 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 5 "new beginning", undated; 57293 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 5 "The Revolution Postponed", undated; 57292 (Box 3, Folder 15A)
    - Chapter 6 "rerum novarum", undated; 57291 (Box 3, Folder 15B)
    - Chapter 7 "Third International", undated; 57290 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 8 "Third International" (continued), undated; 57289 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 9 "the far east", undated; 57288 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Chapter l3 "California in 1931-32", undated; 57287 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 15 "King cotton", undated; 57286 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Chapter l6 "West coast maritime strike/San Francisco general strike, undated; 57285 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 17 "San Francisco general strike", undated; 57284 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 18 "a lost opportunity", undated; 57283 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 19 "the communist international - 7th & last congress", undated; 57282 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 20 "the Moscow trials", undated; 57281 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 21 "eve of catastrophe in west Europe", undated; 57280 (Box 3, Folder 25A)
    - Chapter 22 "tale of two states", undated; 57279 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 23 "one account is paid", undated; 57278 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 24 "the dissolution of the communist international", undated; 57277 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 25 "the earlier crop of `creative Marxists'", undated; 57276 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Chapter 26 "a tale of how Browder made Marx more creative", undated; 57275 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Subseries B. Oral history interview transcripts and notes., 57269
    - SAD notes on interview by Harry Stein, 1969; 57273 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Transcript of interview by Ron Filipelli, undated; 57272 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - second of two interviews, 1971; 57271 (Box 3, Folder data_value_missing_2e0cdf68dbcb45d6c1e65c7e3f58c926)
    - Wormser, Richard - Interview notes & documents, 1981; 57270 (Box 3, Folder 32A)
  - Subseries C. Tale of three worlds (unpublished ms.) ca 1960-63, 57263
    - Tale of three worlds, book 1 ca 1960-63, ca.1960-1963; 57268 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Tale of three worlds, book 2 ca 1960-63, ca.1960-1963; 57267 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Tale of three worlds, book 3 ca 1960-63, ca.1960-1963; 57266 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Tale of three worlds, book 4 ca 1960-63, ca.1960-1963; 57265 (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
    - Tale of three worlds, book 5 ca 1960-63, ca.1960-1963; 57264 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Subseries D. Play and poetry, 57260
    - The second revolution (play), 1974; 57262 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Poetry, ca.1981; 57261 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Subseries E. Miscellaneous post-1945 notes, 57254
    - Bullitt, William: Darcy Notes re WB and Russian Revolution, undated; 57259 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - A Fresh Look at the Christian Crusades as the Past Lay Dying (ts, 18 pp.), undated; 57258 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous post, 1945 notes undated., ca.1940-1950; 57257 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - References to, reviews re SAD, undated; 57256 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Sam Darcy Studies, no. 1-6, 1979-1980; 57255 (Box 4, Folder 7)